americanexpress.com.bh 2019-06-11

# American Express Bahrain - Website Rules

### Data Protection and Privacy Policy

#### Effective Date: July 12, 2018

The following Data Protection and Privacy Policy sets out the way that AMEX (Middle East) B.S.C. (c). will collect, use, store, share, transmit, delete or otherwise process (collectively “process”) your personal data. Personal data means any information that relates to an identified or identifiable individual.

Since we may change this privacy statement, we recommend that you check the current version available from time to time. If we make changes to this statement, we will update the “Effective Date” at the top of this page.

### Data Collection

We will only collect personal data that is needed and by lawful and fair means.

### Data Processing

We will process your personal data fairly as permitted / required by applicable law.

### Data Disclosure

We only share your personal data with third parties (e.g. service providers, credit bureaus, regulatory authorities, etc.) where it is necessary in order to provide you with products or services or as part of the nature of our relationship with you, where we have previously informed or been authorized by you, in connection with our efforts to reduce fraud or criminal activity, or as permitted / required by law.

### Data Security and Confidentiality

We will keep your personal data confidential and limit access to your personal data to those who specifically need it to conduct their business activities, except as otherwise permitted by applicable law. We refer to industry standards and use reasonable administrative, technical and physical security measures to protect your personal data from unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification or disclosure. We require industry standard data security measures from those third parties who are authorized by us to process your personal data on our behalf.

### Responsibility

AMEX (Middle East) B.S.C. (c) and its employees process your personal data in accordance with this policy.

These principles emphasize our commitment to protect your personal data. They are binding on AMEX (Middle East) B.S.C. (c), demonstrating our commitment to privacy.

This Online privacy statement is an agreement between you and AMEX (Middle East) B.S.C. (c) and applies to our websites, online applications that run on smart phones, tablets, mobile devices (“apps”), and other online services that we offer which link to this statement. Customers should be aware that it does not apply to those websites, apps and online services that have their own privacy statements that differ from the provisions provided herein. AMEX (Middle East) B.S.C. (c) is not responsible for such provisions, and expressly disclaims any and all liability related to such provisions.

### What information does this privacy statement cover?

This online privacy statement describes how we (and our Service Providers) may collect, use, store, share, transmit, delete or otherwise process (collectively “process”) your personal data. We gather online information if you visit or use our website or app, or receive or reply to electronic communications from us, for example. Online Information represents data or information collected on the AMEX (Middle East) B.S.C. (c) websites and app as well as on websites and apps of third parties relating to topics about our business.

### What information do we collect online and how do we collect it?

The types of information we collect depends on which product or service you use.

Sometimes you give information directly to us (or to our Service Providers). For example, you might give us your name, email, mailing address, phone number, or date of birth when you fill out an online form, or register, log into or update the settings on your account using our online services.

We also collect information through the app by using the location of your mobile device for location-based services that you may request (once you register to receive location-based content), accessing your device information and also your phone contact details to refer friends (once you enable it). 

We also collect information through cookies and similar technologies. Cookies are small text files which are placed on your computer (or Smartphone or other device used to access the internet) whenever you visit a website. We use cookies for different reasons, including enhancing your visit to our website. The cookies we place on your computer cannot be used to retrieve any other data from your hard drive, to pass viruses to your computer, or capture your e-mail address. Some of the functions that cookies perform can also be achieved using alternative technology hence we use the term 'cookies and similar technologies ' in this notice. Cookies & similar technologies serve several functions. Most cookies & similar technologies won’t collect information that identifies you, and will instead collect more general information such as how users arrive at a website or app.

### How do we use the information we collect about you?

We may use online information that we collect about you on its own or combine it with other information such as Card transaction data, external data that financial companies use to process applications and complete transactions, and other information we collect from you to deliver products and services, conduct research and analysis, manage fraud, security, and risk, ensure proper billing and inform you about products and services, for example.

If you provide us with your email address, we may, for example, upon occasion send you email offers. All offers are carefully developed to ensure that they meet our standards. Our goal is to target offers at people who we believe will find them of value. The lists used to send you products and services offers are developed and managed under strict conditions designed to safeguard the security and privacy of customer personal information.

If you have questions or comments about this privacy policy, please [contact us](https://secure.americanexpress.com.bh/wps/portal/bahrain/!ut/p/a1/04_Sj9CPykssy0xPLMnMz0vMAfGjzOKNDT1dDYycDbwMHN3NDDz9jNwNAwwsjFzcDIAKIoEKDHAARwNC-sP1o8BKnN0dPUzMfYB6Qt1dDDzNA51C_X29jQ08zaAK8FhRkBthkOmoqAgASB7E_Q!!/dl5/d5/L2dJQSEvUUt3QS80SmlFL1o2X0tQNDBIODgySTg4SEYwSTc0SFMwVkowMEE1/ "Contact us") at AMEX (Middle East) B.S.C. (c).
